What do augmented reality
ما علاقة الواقع المدمج
and professional football
وكرة القدم للمحترفين
have to do with empathy?
بالتواصل الحسي؟
And what is the air speed velocity
وما هي سرعة الطيران
of an unladen swallow?
لطائر السنونو الغير مُمتلئ؟
Now unfortunately, I'm only going to answer
لسوء الحظ، لن أجيب اليوم إلا على سؤالٍ
one of those questions today,
واحدٍ من هذه الأسئلة
so please, try and contain your disappointment.
لذا فضلًا حاولوا أن تحتووا إحباطكم.
When most people think about augmented reality,
حينما يفكر أغلب الناس في الواقع المدمج
they think about "Minority Report" and Tom Cruise
يفكرون في فيلم " ماينوريتي ريبورت" وتوم كروز
waving his hands in the air,
يلوِح بيديه في الهواء،
but augmented reality is not science fiction.
لكن الواقع المدمج ليس خيالًا علميًا.
Augmented reality is something that will happen
الواقع المدمج هو شيء سوف يحدث
in our lifetime, and it will happen
في حياتنا، وسوف يحدث
because we have the tools to make it happen,
لأننا نملك الأدوات لتحقيق ذلك،
and people need to be aware of that,
وعلى الناس أن يدركوا ذلك،
because augmented reality will change our lives
لأن الواقع المدمج سوف يغير حياتنا
just as much as the Internet and the cell phone.
تمامًا بنفس القدر الذي غيره كل من الإنترنت والهاتف المحمول.
Now how do we get to augmented reality?
حسنًا كيف نصل إلى الواقع المدمج؟
Step one is the step I'm wearing right now,
الخطوة الأولى هي الخطوة التي أرتديها الآن،
Google Glass.
نظارة غوغل.
I'm sure many of you are familiar with Google Glass.
أنا متيقن أن نظارة جوجل مألوفة لعديد منكم
What you may not be familiar with
ما قد لا تألفونه
is that Google Glass is a device
هو أن نظارة غوغل هي جهاز
that will allow you to see what I see.
يسمح لكم برؤية ما أرى.
It will allow you to experience what it is like
ستمسح لكم بتجربة شعور
to be a professional athlete on the field.
أن تكون رياضيًا محترفًا في الميدان.
Right now, the only way you can be on the field
الأن، الطريقة الوحيدة لتكون في الميدان
is for me to try and describe it to you.
هي أن أقوم بمحاولة وصفه لكم.
I have to use words.
يجب أن أستخدم كلمات.
I have to create a framework that you then fill in
يجب عليَّ أن أنشئ إطارًا لتقوموا أنتم بملئه
with your imagination.
بمخيلاتكم.
With Google Glass, we can put that
مع نظارة غوغل، يمكننا وضع هذا
underneath a helmet,
تحت خوذة،
and we can get a sense of what it's like
ويمكننا أن نشعر بما يشبه
to be running down the field at 100 miles an hour,
العدو في الميدان بسرعة 100 ميل في الساعة،
your blood pounding in your ears.
يخفق الدم في أذنيك،
You can get a sense of what it's like
يمكنك الشعور بما يشبه
to have a 250-pound man
وجود رجلٍ يزن 250 رطلًا
sprinting at you
يركض نحوك
trying to decapitate you
يحاول قطع رأسك
with every ounce of his being.
بكل كيانه.
And I've been on the receiving end of that,
ولقد كنت في الطرف المتلقي لهذا
and it doesn't feel very good.
وليس شعورًا جيدًا.
Now, I have some footage to show you of what it's like
الآن، لدي بعض اللقطات لأريكم ما يشبه
to wear Google Glass underneath the helmet
ارتداء نظارة جوجل تحت خوذة
to give you a taste of that.
لأعطيكم هذا الإحساس.
Unfortunately, it's not NFL practice footage
ولسوء الحظ ليست لقطات من دوري كرة القدم المحلي
because the NFL thinks emergent technology
لأن دوري كرة القدم يعتقد أن التكنولوجيا الناشئة
is what happens when a submarine surfaces,
هو ما يحدث حين تطفو غواصة،
but — (Laughter) — we do what we can.
لكننا - (ضحك) - نقوم بما يمكننا.
So let's pull up some video.
إذًا، دعونا نشاهد بعض الفيديوهات.
(Video) Chris Kluwe: Go.
كريس كلو (فيديو): هيا.
Ugh, getting tackled sucks.
آه، التعرض للاصطدام أمرٌ مريع.
Hold on, let's get a little closer.
مهلًا دعونا نقترب قليلًا.
All right, ready?
جاهز؟
Go!
هيا!
Chris Kluwe: So as you can see,
كريس كلو: إذًا كما ترون،
small taste of what it's like to get tackled
إحساس بسيط بما يشبه تعرضكم لاصطدام
on the football field
في ملعب كرة قدم
from the perspective of the tacklee.
من منظور المعترض للخصم.
Now, you may have noticed there are
الآن، ربما لاحظتم أن هناك
some people missing there:
بعض الناس غيرموجودين:
the rest of the team.
بقية الفريق.
We have some video of that
لدينا فيديو عن ذلك
courtesy of the University of Washington.
هدية من جامعة واشنطن
(Video) Quarterback: Hey, Mice 54! Mice 54!
(فيديو) لاعب الوسط الرئيسي: هيا، الفئران 54! الفئران 54!
Blue 8! Blue 8! Go!
أزرق 8! أزرق 8! هيا!
Oh!
آه!
CK: So again, this takes you a little bit closer
كريس كلو: ثانيةً هذا يجعلكم أقرب قليلًا
to what it's like to be on that field,
لما يشبه أن تكون في الملعب،
but this is nowhere what it's like
لكن هذا ليس قريبًا حتى
to be on the NFL.
من أن تكون في دوري كرة القدم المحلي.
Fans want that experience.
المشجعون يريدون تلك التجربة.
Fans want to be on that field.
يريدون التواجد في الملعب
They want to be their favorite players,
يريدون أن يكونوا لاعبيهم المفضلين،
and they've already talked to me on YouTube,
ولقد تحدثوا معي بالفعل عبر اليوتيوب،
they've talked to me on Twitter, saying,
وعبر تويتر، قائلون،
"Hey, can you get this on a quarterback?
"هل يمكن تطبيق ذلك على لاعب الوسط الرئيسي؟
Can you get this on a running back?
أوعلى لاعب الخلف؟
We want that experience."
نريد تلك التجربة."
Well, once we have that experience with GoPro
حسنًا، بمجرد أن نحصل على تلك التجربة مع جوبرو
and Google Glass,
ونظارة غوغل،
how do we make it more immersive?
كيف يمكن أن تغمرالمستخدم أكثر
How do we take that next step?
كيف نخطو الخطوة التالية؟
Well, we take that step
حسنًا، خطونا تلك الخطوة
by going to something called the Oculus Rift,
بواسطة ما يسمى أوكيوليس ريفت
which I'm sure many of you are also familiar with.
وأنا متأكدٌ أن العديد منكم يألفونه.
The Oculus Rift has been described as one of
ويُوصف الأوكيوليس ريفت كواحدٍ من
the most realistic virtual reality devices ever created,
أكثر أجهزة الواقع الافتراضي التي تم اختراعها واقعيةً على الإطلاق،
and that is not empty hype.
وهذا ليس صخبًا زائفًا.
I'm going to show you why that is not empty hype
أنا بصدد أن أريكم أن هذا ليس بصخب زائف
with this video.
في هذا الفيديو.
(Video) Man: Oh! Oh!
(فيديو) رجل: أه! أه!
No! No! No! I don't want to play anymore! No!
لا! لا! لا! لا أريد أن ألعب ثانيةً! لا!
Oh my God! Aaaah!
يا إلهي! آآآآآآآآآه
CK: So that is the experience of a man
كريس كلو: إذًا هذه تجربة رجل
on a roller coaster
في قطار الموت
in fear of his life.
خائف على حياته.
What do you think that fan's experience
برأيك كيف ستكون تجربة ذلك المشجع
is going to be when we take the video footage
حين نريه لقطة الفيديو
of an Adrian Peterson bursting through the line,
لأدريان بيترسون ينطلق عبر الخط
shedding a tackler with a stiff-arm
معطيًا المدافع ذراعًا قوية
before sprinting in for a touchdown?
قبل أن يركض للمس الأرض؟
What do you think that fan's experience
برأيك كيف ستكون تجربة ذلك المشجع
sprinting down the pitch
راكضًا في الملعب
putting the ball in the back of the net,
واضعًا الكرة خلف الشبكة،
or Federer serving in Wimbledon?
أو فيدريد يرسل الكرة في ويمبلدون؟
What do you think his experience is going to be
برأيك كيف ستكون تجربة ذلك المشجع
when he is going down the side of a mountain
حين ينزلق أسفل جانب جبل
at over 70 miles an hour
بسرعة أكثر من 70 ميل في الساعة
as an Olympic downhill skier?
كمتزلق تلال أوليمبي؟
I think adult diaper sales may surge.
أعتقد أن مبيعات حفاضات الكبار قد ترتفع.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But this is not yet augmented reality.
لكن هذا ليس الواقع المدمج بعد.
This is only virtual reality, V.R.
هذا هو الواقع الافتراضي فحسب.
How do we get to augmented reality, A.R.?
كيف نتحول للواقع المدمج؟
We get to augmented reality
نتحول للواقع المدمج
when coaches and managers and owners
حين ينظر المدربون والمديرون والمالكون
look at this information streaming in
لهذه المعلومات المتدفقة
that people want to see, and they say,
عن رغبة الناس في المشاهدة
"How do we use this to make our teams better?
ويقولون: "كيف يمكننا استخدام هذا لجعل فرقنا أفضل؟
How do we use this to win games?"
كيف نستخدم هذا للفوز بالمباريات؟"
Because teams always use technology to win games.
لأن الفرق دائمًا تستخدم التكنولوجيا للفوز بالمباريات.
They like winning. It makes them money.
فهم يحبون الفوز. هذا يمنحهم المال.
So a brief history of technology in the NFL.
إذًا لمحة تاريخية مختصرة عن التكنولوجيا في دوري كرة القدم المحلي
In 1965, the Baltimore Colts
في 1965، بولتمور كلوتس
put a wristband on their quarterback
وضع معصم للاعب الوسط الرئيسي
to allow him to call plays quicker.
ليتسنى له استدعاء الألعاب أسرع.
They ended up winning a Super Bowl that year.
فازوا بالسوبر بول هذا العام.
Other teams followed suit.
الفرق الأخرى حاذت حذوها.
More people watched the game because it was more exciting.
شاهد اللعبة أناس أكثر لأنها أصبحت أكثر تشويقًا
It was faster.
كانت أسرع.
In 1994, the NFL put helmet radios
في 1994، وضع دوري كرة القدم المحلي سماعات
into the helmets of the quarterbacks,
داخل خوذات لاعب الوسط الرئيسي
and later the defense.
ثم الدفاع لاحقًا.
More people watched games because it was faster.
شاهد المباريات أناس أكثر لأنها كانت أسرع.
It was more entertaining.
كانت أكثر إمتاعًا.
In 2023, imagine you're a player
في 2023، تخيل أنك لاعب
walking back to the huddle,
تعود إلى الحشد
and you have your next play displayed
وقد عُرضت لعبتك القادمة
right in front of your face on your clear plastic visor
أمام وجهك تمامًا على الواقي البلاستك الشفاف الخاص بك
that you already wear right now.
الذي ترتديه بالفعل الآن.
No more having to worry about forgetting plays.
لا مزيد من القلق حول نسيان الألعاب.
No more worrying about having to memorize your playbook.
لا مزيد من القلق حول حمل كتيب الألعاب لتذكيرك.
You just go out and react.
فقط اخرج وتفاعل.
And coaches really want this,
ويريد المدربون ذلك بشدة،
because missed assignments lose you games,
لأن المهام الناقصة تتسبب في خسارة المباراة
and coaches hate losing games.
ويكره المدربون خسارة المباريات.
Losing games gets you fired as a coach.
فخسارة المباريات تعرضك لفصلك من العمل كمدرب.
They don't want that.
هم لا يريدون ذلك.
But augmented reality is not just
لكن الواقع المدمج ليس مجرد
an enhanced playbook.
كتيب ألعاب مُحسن.
Augmented reality is also a way to take all that data
الواقع المدمج هو أيضًا طريقة للحصول على كل تلك البيانات
and use it in real time
واستخدامها في الوقت الحقيقي
to enhance how you play the game.
لتحسين كيفية لعبك للمباراة.
What would that be like?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
Well, a very simple setup would be a camera
حسنًا، إعدادٌ بسيطٌ جدًا عبارةٌ عن كاميرا
on each corner of the stadium looking down,
في كل ركن من الاستاد موجهة للأسفل
giving you a bird's-eye view
تمنحك رؤية من الأعلى
of all the people down there.
لجميع الناس هناك في الأسفل.
You also have information from helmet sensors
لديك معلومات أيضًا من أجهزة استشعار الخوذة
and accelerometers,
والمتسارعات
technology that's being worked on right now.
التكنولوجيا التي يتم العمل عليها حاليًا
You take all that information, and you stream it to your players.
تأخذ كل تلك المعلومات، وتجعلها تتدفق للاعبيك
The good teams stream it in a way that the players can use.
الفرق الجيدة تجعلها تتدفق بطريقة
That determines good teams from bad.
معلومات زائد.
is just as important as your scouting department,
مهمٌ بقدر أهمية قسم الكشافين
and data-mining is not for nerds anymore.
والتنقيب عن البيانات ليس للمهووسين بعد الآن.
It's also for jocks. Who knew?
كما إنها قد تكون أيضًا للاعبي الأسطوانات من يعرف؟
What would that look like on the field?
كيف سيبدوا ذلك في الملعب؟
Well, imagine you're the quarterback.
حسنًا، تخيل أنك لاعب الوسط الرئيسي.
You take the snap and you drop back.
أخذت التمريرة ثم تراجعت للخلف
You're scanning downfield for an open receiver.
تستكشف الملعب بحثًا عن متلقٍ حر.
All of a sudden, a bright flash
فجأة، ومضة لامعة
on the left side of your visor lets you know,
على الجانب الأيسر من الواقي تعلمك أن
blind side linebacker is blitzing in.
الظهير الجانبي الغير مرئي يركض باتجاهك
Normally, you wouldn't be able to see him,
في الحالة العادية، لن تراه
but the augmented reality system lets you know.
لكن نظام الواقع المدمج يعلمك بذلك.
You step up into the pocket.
تخطو نحو الهدف
Another flash alerts you to an open receiver.
وميض آخر ينبهك لمستقبل حر.
You throw the ball, but you're hit right as you throw.
تمرر الكرة، لكنك ضَربت في لحظة التمرير.
The ball comes off track.
الكرة تبعد عن مسارها
You don't know where it's going to land.
أنت لا تعرف أين سوف تهبط.
However, on the receiver's visor,
على أي حال، على واقي المُستَقبِل،
he sees a patch of grass light up,
يرى رقعة من العشب تضيء
and he knows to readjust.
ويعلم أن عليه التعديل
He goes, catches the ball,
يذهب، ويمسك الكرة،
sprints in, touchdown.
ويركض، ويلمس الأرض.
Crowd goes wild, and the fans are with him
الحشد يمضي متحمس، والمشجعون معه
every step of the way,
في كل خطوة في الطريق،
watching from every perspective.
يشاهدون من كل منظور.
Now this is something that will create
الآن هذا هو الشيء الذي سيخلق
massive excitement in the game.
تشويقًا ضخمًا في المباراة.
It will make tons of people watch,
سوف تجعل كما هائلا من الناس يشاهدون،
because people want this experience.
لأن الناس يريدون هذه التجربة.
Fans want to be on the field.
المشجعون يريدون أن يكونوا في الملعب.
They want to be their favorite player.
يريدون أن يكونوا لاعبهم المفضل.
Augmented reality will be a part of sports,
سيكون الواقع المدمج جزءً من الرياضة،
because it's too profitable not to.
لأنها مربحة جدًا ليس إلا.
But the question I ask you is,
لكن السؤال االذي سأطرحه عليكم هو
is that's all that we're content to use augmented reality for?
هل هذا هو كل ما يمكننا استعمال الواقع المدمج فيه؟
Are we going to use it solely for our panem,
هل سوف نستخدمه فقط لطعامنا،
our circenses, our entertainment as normal?
واستمتاعنا، ومتعتنا كالمألوف؟
Because I believe that we can use augmented reality
لأني أعتقد أننا نستطيع استخدام الواقع المدمج
for something more.
لشيء أكثر.
I believe we can use augmented reality
أنا متيقن من استطاعتنا استخدام الواقع المدمج
as a way to foster more empathy
كطريق لتعزيز التواصل الحسي
within the human species itself,
خلال الأجناس البشرية نفسها،
by literally showing someone
من خلال الإظهار حرفيًا لشخص ما
what it looks like
كيف يبدوا
to walk a mile in another person's shoes.
أخذ مكان شخصٍ آخر.
We know what this technology is worth
نحن نعرف ما قيمة هذه التكنولوجيا
to sports leagues.
للدوريات الرياضية.
It's worth revenue, to the tune of billions of dollars a year.
قيمتها أن تصل الإيرادات لمليارات الدولارات في العام.
But what is this technology worth
لكن ما قيمة هذه التكنولوجيا
to a teacher in a classroom
لمدرس في فصل
trying to show a bully
محاولًا إظهار لمتمردٍ
just how harmful his actions are
ما مدى ضرر أفعاله
from the perspective of the victim?
من منظور الضحية؟
What is this technology worth
ما قيمة هذه التكنولوجيا
to a gay Ugandan or Russian
لشاذ أوغندي أو روسي
trying to show the world what it's like
محاولين إظهار للعالم كيف يكون
living under persecution?
العيش تحت الاضطهاد؟
What is this technology worth
ما قيمة هذه التكنولوجيا
to a Commander Hadfield or a Neil deGrasse Tyson
للكابتين هادفيلد أو نيل ديجراس تايسون
trying to inspire a generation of children
وهم يحاولون إلهام جيلٍ من الأطفال
to think more about space and science
ليفكروا في الفضاء والعلوم أكثر
instead of quarterly reports and Kardashians?
بدلًا من التقارير الربع سنوية وآل كارداشيان؟
Ladies and gentlemen, augmented reality
أيها السيدات والسادة، الواقع المدمج
is coming.
قادم
The questions we ask, the choices we make,
الأسئلة التي نسألها، والاختيارات التي نقوم بها،
and the challenges we face
والتحديات التي نواجهها،
are, as always, up to us.
كالمعتاد، تعود إلينا.
Thank you.
أشكركم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)